<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>viz on 👋 hi, I’m basile</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/tags/viz/</link><description>Recent content in viz on 👋 hi, I’m basile</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basilesimon.fr/tags/viz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Portfolio case study: Machine learning's take on Brexit</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-brexit-rift-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-brexit-rift-machine-learning/</guid><description>An original data-driven experiment looking at how Brexit splits the Tories. Modelling of a dataset to test a hypothesis.
Project course The project came to be as a backburner piece for my contribution to the Europe, Middle East and Africa Reuters file: a kind of backgrounder, explainer story we could mention and push out again every once in a while.
The central question was whether we could back up the feeling Lobby reporters had that there were several groups of Tories, so-called &amp;ldquo;tribes,&amp;rdquo; with different attitudes to Brexit — while Labour parliamentarians were relatively united in pushing back against Theresa May&amp;rsquo;s deal.</description></item><item><title>Comparing Berlin memorial street plaques datasets</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/stolpersteine-maps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/stolpersteine-maps/</guid><description>Here are two quite different datasets, which supposedly represent the same thing. Hard to miss how different is the extent of their geographical coverage.
🔸 Wikidata reference 🔹 Stolpersteine-berlin dataset View on Observable
Background In the night of Nov 9 to 10, 1938, Nazi Germany&amp;rsquo;s SA forces carried out a devastating pogrom. The event came to be called Kristallnacht, &amp;ldquo;The Night of Broken Glass.&amp;quot;
Last week, as I walked in the street in the evening I noticed that some of the brass plques had candles and roses next to them, a silent and unattended vigil in the street.</description></item><item><title>Portfolio case study: Reuters' 2019 general election results page</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-general-election-2019-britain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-general-election-2019-britain/</guid><description>A node backend and a modular, reactive front page visualising the UK general election results, as they happened. For Reuters Graphics.
Unfortunately, this page was deleted from the internet.
Front end: the results page The page was built to be modular, i.e. to work this way:
clients must be able to pick and choose which graphics they want, from one of them to all of them, there is only one repository of code I update and push out to clients.</description></item><item><title>A beeswarm layout in Observable -- on deadline</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/observable-beeswarm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/observable-beeswarm/</guid><description>I recently had to complete a technical test for a role I&amp;rsquo;m interested in.
The task: from a story out of the Global Witness website, can you come up with an alternative visualisation? You&amp;rsquo;ve got two hours.
As there were no embed constraints, I figured there was no point in faffing with boilerplate code and scaffolds, so I went down the Observable route to put a chart together.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what we need scales-wise:</description></item><item><title>Portfolio case study: Global Witness' Pipedown interactive map</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-global-witness-pipedown-map/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-global-witness-pipedown-map/</guid><description>An interactive map of natural gas infrastructure in the EU, built with Svelte and d3, for Global Witness.
Some context The EU has a rule in place to regulate which electricity and fossil fuel projects it will financially support. These projects include the terminals and pipelines used to import and transport fossil gas – sometimes referred to as natural gas. Under this regulation, selected gas projects get fast-track approval and access to billions in public subsidies.</description></item><item><title>Exercising in a 1km radius (another Strava data viz)</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/1km-covid-viz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/1km-covid-viz/</guid><description>So, I&amp;rsquo;m in France right now, and with this lockdown going on we&amp;rsquo;re quite restricted on the physical exercise front.
Technically we&amp;rsquo;re allowed to go out for a sweat, but can&amp;rsquo;t go for longer than an hour a day, and no further than a one-kilometre radius away rom home.
With this in mind and for no particular reason I set off to cycle, run, or walk every street in this virtual confinement circle.</description></item><item><title>Machine learning's take on the Brexit's House of Commons</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/brexit-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/brexit-machine-learning/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say things are a little confused over here in Brexit Land. To put it lightly, it has become difficult to explain, or simply to fathom what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next.
A few months ago I looked at the rift splitting the Conservative Party, but the topic kept nagging me.
Obviously the &amp;ldquo;indicative votes&amp;rdquo; were a great tool to identify the Brexit &amp;ldquo;tribes,&amp;quot; as they represented such varied opinions, allowing us to build a mental picture of the different kinds of Brexit MPs could support.</description></item><item><title>Strava rides map in R</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/strava-rides-map-in-r/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/strava-rides-map-in-r/</guid><description>This is a Christmas present to myself to celebrate 10,000km of commuting on my bicycle: a lovely frame print of all my GPS traces on a home-made map of London. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I made it.
This blog was contributed to R Bloggers
Step one: getting Strava data The process has become slightly convoluted in May 2018. In the past, it was possible to download a Strava archive which contained all activities as GPX; however, GDPR regulations led to a change in bulk export format.</description></item><item><title>Mapping storms in R</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/storms-map-in-r/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/storms-map-in-r/</guid><description>Japan is currently counting the cost of the strongest typhoon to hit its coasts in 25 years. The death toll currently stands at nine, and hundreds were injured.
The north western Pacific basin sees many storms, and meteorology agencies release loads of data about climate events such as these. For this example, we are going to use the work of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, which releases datasets known as International Best Track Archive for Climate Stewardship.</description></item></channel></rss>