<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on 👋 hi, I’m basile</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on 👋 hi, I’m basile</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basilesimon.fr/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New book chapter out in the Data Journalism Handbook</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/data-journalism-handbook-published/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/data-journalism-handbook-published/</guid><description>The updated version of The Data Journalism Handbook was published this week – a huge relief for Liliana Bounegru and Jonathan Gray, its editors, who have been working on this for years.
I contributed a chapter: “Coding with data in the newsroom”, which you&amp;rsquo;ll find in the second section, “Working with data”, nicely tucked between Barbara Maseda&amp;rsquo;s “Text as data: finding stories in text collections” 😎 and Sam Leon&amp;rsquo;s “Accounting for methods: spreadsheets, scripts and programming notebooks.</description></item><item><title>Announcing the Digital Evidence Toolkit</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/announcing-digital-evidence-toolkit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/announcing-digital-evidence-toolkit/</guid><description>🎉
I&amp;rsquo;m very exited to announce that the Digital Evidence Preservation Toolkit is being funded by the Prototype Fund, a joint venture of the Open Knowledge Foundation and of the Federal Ministry of Education and Research!
Every day, dedicated investigative journalists and human rights monitors scour the Web in search of proof of abuse, wrongdoing, and crime. The material they gather is at risk of being ruled inadmissible and dismissed out of hand in court.</description></item><item><title>Some declarative, React-like logic for your Observable/d3 toolkit</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/hello-d3-render/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/hello-d3-render/</guid><description>Earlier this week, as I was looking into idiomatic ways of updating a chart, I came across Kaho Cheung&amp;rsquo;s d3-render &amp;ndash; and boy did I get excited.
d3-render packages up a bunch of d3 commands in a declarative shell, inspired by a eather functional and reactive approach. @unkleho has got a lovely tutorial introducing the library, but here&amp;rsquo;s another one from yours truly anyway.
Implementation It&amp;rsquo;s going to work this way:</description></item><item><title>Portfolio case study: Machine learning's take on Brexit</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-brexit-rift-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-brexit-rift-machine-learning/</guid><description>An original data-driven experiment looking at how Brexit splits the Tories. Modelling of a dataset to test a hypothesis.
Project course The project came to be as a backburner piece for my contribution to the Europe, Middle East and Africa Reuters file: a kind of backgrounder, explainer story we could mention and push out again every once in a while.
The central question was whether we could back up the feeling Lobby reporters had that there were several groups of Tories, so-called &amp;ldquo;tribes,&amp;rdquo; with different attitudes to Brexit — while Labour parliamentarians were relatively united in pushing back against Theresa May&amp;rsquo;s deal.</description></item><item><title>Comparing Berlin memorial street plaques datasets</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/stolpersteine-maps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/stolpersteine-maps/</guid><description>Here are two quite different datasets, which supposedly represent the same thing. Hard to miss how different is the extent of their geographical coverage.
🔸 Wikidata reference 🔹 Stolpersteine-berlin dataset View on Observable
Background In the night of Nov 9 to 10, 1938, Nazi Germany&amp;rsquo;s SA forces carried out a devastating pogrom. The event came to be called Kristallnacht, &amp;ldquo;The Night of Broken Glass.&amp;quot;
Last week, as I walked in the street in the evening I noticed that some of the brass plques had candles and roses next to them, a silent and unattended vigil in the street.</description></item><item><title>Portfolio case study: Reuters' 2019 general election results page</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-general-election-2019-britain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-general-election-2019-britain/</guid><description>A node backend and a modular, reactive front page visualising the UK general election results, as they happened. For Reuters Graphics.
Unfortunately, this page was deleted from the internet.
Front end: the results page The page was built to be modular, i.e. to work this way:
clients must be able to pick and choose which graphics they want, from one of them to all of them, there is only one repository of code I update and push out to clients.</description></item><item><title>A beeswarm layout in Observable -- on deadline</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/observable-beeswarm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/observable-beeswarm/</guid><description>I recently had to complete a technical test for a role I&amp;rsquo;m interested in.
The task: from a story out of the Global Witness website, can you come up with an alternative visualisation? You&amp;rsquo;ve got two hours.
As there were no embed constraints, I figured there was no point in faffing with boilerplate code and scaffolds, so I went down the Observable route to put a chart together.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what we need scales-wise:</description></item><item><title>Portfolio case study: Global Witness' Pipedown interactive map</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-global-witness-pipedown-map/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-global-witness-pipedown-map/</guid><description>An interactive map of natural gas infrastructure in the EU, built with Svelte and d3, for Global Witness.
Some context The EU has a rule in place to regulate which electricity and fossil fuel projects it will financially support. These projects include the terminals and pipelines used to import and transport fossil gas – sometimes referred to as natural gas. Under this regulation, selected gas projects get fast-track approval and access to billions in public subsidies.</description></item><item><title>Exercising in a 1km radius (another Strava data viz)</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/1km-covid-viz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/1km-covid-viz/</guid><description>So, I&amp;rsquo;m in France right now, and with this lockdown going on we&amp;rsquo;re quite restricted on the physical exercise front.
Technically we&amp;rsquo;re allowed to go out for a sweat, but can&amp;rsquo;t go for longer than an hour a day, and no further than a one-kilometre radius away rom home.
With this in mind and for no particular reason I set off to cycle, run, or walk every street in this virtual confinement circle.</description></item><item><title>Machine learning's take on the Brexit's House of Commons</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/brexit-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/brexit-machine-learning/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say things are a little confused over here in Brexit Land. To put it lightly, it has become difficult to explain, or simply to fathom what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next.
A few months ago I looked at the rift splitting the Conservative Party, but the topic kept nagging me.
Obviously the &amp;ldquo;indicative votes&amp;rdquo; were a great tool to identify the Brexit &amp;ldquo;tribes,&amp;quot; as they represented such varied opinions, allowing us to build a mental picture of the different kinds of Brexit MPs could support.</description></item><item><title>noaastorms R package now supports NOAA IBTrACS v4</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/update-noaastorms-r-package/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/update-noaastorms-r-package/</guid><description>Earlier this year, I released a simple R package (available at basilesimon/noaastorms) that downloads, cleans and parses NOAA IBtrack data for you.
As the NOAA updated its datasets, noaastorms is now using these!
How to install library(devtools) install_github(&amp;#34;basilesimon/noaastorms&amp;#34;) Available functions getStorms: Fetch NOAA historical best track storms data
&amp;gt; df &amp;lt;- getStorms(c(&amp;#39;EP&amp;#39;)) &amp;gt; head(df[1:5]) Serial_Num Season Num Basin Sub_basin Name 2 1902276N14266 1902 01 EP MM UNNAMED 3 1902276N14266 1902 01 EP MM UNNAMED 4 1902276N14266 1902 01 EP MM UNNAMED 5 1902276N14266 1902 01 EP MM UNNAMED 6 1902276N14266 1902 01 EP MM UNNAMED The first argument is a vector of basin codes from this list:</description></item><item><title>Tractatus Logico (Phylo)sophicus</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/tractatus-logico-philosophicus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/tractatus-logico-philosophicus/</guid><description>Over the Christmas holidays, I read &amp;ldquo;Maths Meets Myths: Quantitative Approaches to Ancient Narratives,&amp;quot; from the Springer Understanding Complex Systems collection.
The authors present their application of &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; science techniques to datasets coming from the humanities &amp;ndash; mostly large corpus of texts, legends and myths.
One paper in particular uses bioinformatics and phylogenetics to study the spread of a popular folk tale: Little Red Riding Hood. The story that I knew from Perrult and Grimm has patterns that are also found in African and East Asian tales.</description></item><item><title>New R package: load and chart oceanic storms</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/noaastorms-r-package/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/noaastorms-r-package/</guid><description>Mapping historical storms data is now a little bit easier. Off the back of this blog, I have authored an R package (available at basilesimon/noaastorms) that downloads, cleans and parses NOAA IBtrack data for you.
The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration releases datasets known as International Best Track Archive for Climate Stewardship.
These datasets are updated regulary and cover all our oceans. The data found in there is fantasticly detailed and goes back as far as 1850 in some case (I wonder how!</description></item><item><title>Strava rides map in R</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/strava-rides-map-in-r/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/strava-rides-map-in-r/</guid><description>This is a Christmas present to myself to celebrate 10,000km of commuting on my bicycle: a lovely frame print of all my GPS traces on a home-made map of London. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I made it.
This blog was contributed to R Bloggers
Step one: getting Strava data The process has become slightly convoluted in May 2018. In the past, it was possible to download a Strava archive which contained all activities as GPX; however, GDPR regulations led to a change in bulk export format.</description></item><item><title>Pen plotter maps in R</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/pen-plotter-maps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/pen-plotter-maps/</guid><description>I made a sweet Christmas present for my friend Clément, who cycles far too much. Last year he got himself a nice custom bicycle made and started documenting his travels.
So I grabbed the lot and started playing, and I pen-plotted his journeys on postcards.
This blog was contributed to R Bloggers
Base map First order of business is getting and representing borders of the countries travelled. Arcane base R beware.</description></item><item><title>Mapping storms in R</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/storms-map-in-r/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/storms-map-in-r/</guid><description>Japan is currently counting the cost of the strongest typhoon to hit its coasts in 25 years. The death toll currently stands at nine, and hundreds were injured.
The north western Pacific basin sees many storms, and meteorology agencies release loads of data about climate events such as these. For this example, we are going to use the work of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, which releases datasets known as International Best Track Archive for Climate Stewardship.</description></item><item><title>Notes from OpenVis 2018</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/openvis-notes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/openvis-notes/</guid><description>This year, the OpenVis conference took place in Paris. And it was awesome.
Formerly Boston-based, OpenVis made the trip to France and set up shop next to the Tour Eiffel thanks to the support of EM Lyon business school (and of the sponsors), which supported Lynn&amp;rsquo;s desire to keep the conference alive.
Practitioners from around the world are surely grateful for what Lynn and the committee put together this year. I certainly am!</description></item><item><title>We need better career paths for news nerds, a reading list</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/ijf18-career-paths-for-news-nerds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/ijf18-career-paths-for-news-nerds/</guid><description>Joy of joys, I am in Italy again.
This year again, I came to Perugia for the International Journalism Festival, where I moderated a panel about career paths for news nerds.
Or lack thereof, really.
I invited Lisa, Nikki and Martin to come for this chat following my teaser Nieman Lab &amp;ldquo;prediction&amp;rdquo; from December last year.
Here is the reading list we compiled &amp;ldquo;Interactive Journalism - Hackers, Data, and Code&amp;rdquo;, Nikki Usher, 2016 &amp;ldquo;Journalists, meet your new overlords: when nerds run the show&amp;rdquo;, will take place on Sat April 14th panel, Sala del Dottorato &amp;ldquo;In defense of unicorns&amp;rdquo;, Chase Davis, February 2014 The New York Times Innovation report, March 2014 &amp;ldquo;If Data Visualization is so hot, why are people leaving the field?</description></item><item><title>Lessons from teaching in this year's MA in Interactive Journalism</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/jom299-interactive-journalism-year-2-end/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/jom299-interactive-journalism-year-2-end/</guid><description>End of term. No more lectures planned until next year. A few weeks to wait while the students complete their final projects and frantically email me questions.
This year was quite different from the last one. Here&amp;rsquo;s what we covered in the &amp;ldquo;Advanced Data and Coding&amp;rdquo; module, part of City University&amp;rsquo;s Interactive Journalism MA.
Module outline We started off by talking about the web and the HTML-CSS-Javascript triangle. We ran through some exercises together, emphasising the concept of the DOM and how these three languages interact with the DOM through its API.</description></item><item><title>Opening The Times Dataviz Catalogue</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/open-sourcing-times-dataviz-catalogue/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/open-sourcing-times-dataviz-catalogue/</guid><description>Today, we are happy to share the first version of our data visualisation catalogue: a collection of data visualisations created for the Times and Sunday Times, collected together in one place in the hope that what we have learned can be useful to others.
Our goal is to compile and showcase the best of our burgeoning data visualisation work, rather than to offer a taxonomy of visual journalism (the FT’s Visual Vocabulary is a fantastic resource for that).</description></item><item><title>The Times poll of polls in d3</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/times-ge2017-poll-of-polls-d3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/times-ge2017-poll-of-polls-d3/</guid><description>There was quite a bit of excitement in the newsroom when news came in that prime minister Theresa May, contrary to her promises, was calling for a snap election on May 8, 2017.
For us, well, that means a slight change of plans. Throwing the forward planning stuff away and focusing on the big event to come.
For me, that meant jumping on building our lead graphics for the weeks to come: the poll of polls.</description></item><item><title>The Times and The Sunday Times are now HTTPS</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/2017-04-11-the-times-sunday-times-https/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/2017-04-11-the-times-sunday-times-https/</guid><description>I was apparently bullied into opening an account on Medium (for the second time). This content is mine, not theirs, so I reproduced it below.
Two days ago, many months of hard work by multiple teams in our Technology department came to fruition. At 1am they flipped a switch which added an “s” and a tiny green lock in the address bar when you visit our website, accompanied by a reassuring message: “Secure.</description></item><item><title>The Times and The Sunday Times are now HTTPS</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/the-times-sunday-times-https/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/the-times-sunday-times-https/</guid><description>I was apparently bullied into opening an account on Medium (for the second time). This content is mine, not theirs, so I reproduced it below.
Two days ago, many months of hard work by multiple teams in our Technology department came to fruition. At 1am they flipped a switch which added an “s” and a tiny green lock in the address bar when you visit our website, accompanied by a reassuring message: “Secure.</description></item><item><title>Open sourcing my MA in Interactive Journalism lecturing notes</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/notes-on-masters-in-interactive-journalism/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/notes-on-masters-in-interactive-journalism/</guid><description>This year, I have the privilege to be teaching at City university, as part of the MA in Interactive Journalism.
The Times and the Digital team have been extraordinarily supportive of both the idea and of me taking a few hours on Friday mornings to give my lectures - for which I&amp;rsquo;m very grateful.
&amp;ldquo;All knowledge should be free&amp;rdquo;, etc. So, all my presentations and notes are freely accessible on Github.</description></item><item><title>January Transfer Window graphics in The Times</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/january-transfer-window-on-the-times/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/january-transfer-window-on-the-times/</guid><description>I never thought I&amp;rsquo;d talk about football this much, but here you go.
I spent the last weeks working on a rather massive piece looking at the January Transfer Window, this time of year where extraordinary sums are spent to convince men to come kick in a ball somewhere else.
Read the whole piece and the club-by-club analysis on The Times. Note: you can now register for free and benefit from two free articles.</description></item></channel></rss>