<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Weeknotes on 👋 hi, I’m basile</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/</link><description>Recent content in Weeknotes on 👋 hi, I’m basile</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Not so momentous after all - weeknotes #48</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-48/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-48/</guid><description>There is no overarching theme to this week&amp;rsquo;s notes. These two weeks (this past, about which you&amp;rsquo;re reading, and this coming, during which you&amp;rsquo;re reading this) are a bit of a lull:
The grant for the Toolkit is ending but has not quite ended yet ; we&amp;rsquo;re about to go away on holiday ; and I&amp;rsquo;m contemplating being back to my previous projects in a few weeks' time.
The end of the grant will be a sort of send off, a deluge of social media promotion of our projects.</description></item><item><title>The beginning of the end - weeknotes #47</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-47/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-47/</guid><description>This week felt like the beginning of the end of my grant dedicated to working on the Digital Evidence Toolkit. There were two internal deadlines having to do with public comms that will take place over the next two weeks, which meant that there was quite a lot to rush through so it would make MVP.
Time to relax, then? Well, I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure. This coming week is busy with pitch meetings and I&amp;rsquo;ve got the feeling it&amp;rsquo;s actually only the easy part that&amp;rsquo;s ending now: in two weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll be out there with what I&amp;rsquo;ve built, other jobs to do and no booked time to focus on the Toolkit anymore.</description></item><item><title>Expect not too much personal news - weeknotes #46</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-46/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-46/</guid><description>Second-to-last business week before submitting the v1.0 deliverables for the Digital Evidence Toolkit. Perhaps unsurprisingly, it&amp;rsquo;s all I did this week.
Last week, I wrote:
Turns out I’m being asked to show the product a lot. My answer so far is that it’s visually un-interesting and that the value proposition is in the technicalities more than in the design. Still, I feel I should oblige.
To help me with this, I commissioned La Loma, a Berlin-based design agency whose visual vocabulary I really love.</description></item><item><title>The pace picks up - weeknotes #45</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-45/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-45/</guid><description>Big week on the Digital Evidence Toolkit. We&amp;rsquo;re in the home stretch and I feel the pressure mounting.
I spent a bit of time doing further work on editing records, as well as designing some of the static assets for promotion, social media, etc. Turns out I&amp;rsquo;m being asked to show the product a lot.
My answer so far is that it&amp;rsquo;s visually un-interesting and that the value proposition is in the technicalities more than in the design.</description></item><item><title>Second shot, missed tile - weeknotes</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-44/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-44/</guid><description>I got to visit the Berlin Velodrom, though not to dawdle and look at pretty track bikes but to receive my second shot. In keeping with my life story so far, I received the Pfizer/BionTech (🇩🇪) after a first injection of Astra (🇬🇧).
Spent a work day at a new coworking in Neukölln, with an AC, a pantry full of fruits and drinks, and a symmetrical gigabit connection. As I wrote before: it&amp;rsquo;s the leaving to work and the being away at work that feels different.</description></item><item><title>Back to Germany - weeknotes #43</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-43/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-43/</guid><description>Wow, this feels like the beginning of the week was a really long time away. We&amp;rsquo;re now back in Berlin and getting in the groove again. We&amp;rsquo;ve got daycare, I&amp;rsquo;ve got my work setup and my bikes.
Earlier this week, on our last evening in France, we even had our second evening out while my parents looked after the little one.
I sinked more than a half-day on debugging an issue with Gatsby.</description></item><item><title>Short week shot note - weeknotes #42</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-42/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-42/</guid><description>Once again, hello from France, though from quite a bit more South than previously. It&amp;rsquo;s been pouring for the last three weeks in Lyon, so we drove down to la Drôme provençale: the bit in between Lyon and the Riviera/Marseille, a lovely and quiet piece of nature.
Coaching session on Thursday. We moved from &amp;ldquo;North Star&amp;rdquo; metrics we set last time to road-mapping.
The end of the grant period is nigh, and having an external point of view on the schedule and the MVP bucket list.</description></item><item><title>First-class history hoops - weeknotes #41</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-41/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-41/</guid><description>Still in France. I&amp;rsquo;ve not dont a tremendous amount of work this week due to a general lack of time and focus. Everybody&amp;rsquo;s doing their best but sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s just challenging.
Work opportunities keep coming – and I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for it. Most notable this week was a job for the Bureau of Investigative Journalism, which looks manageable in time and quite interesting.
Good progress on the Digital Evidence Toolkit.</description></item><item><title>The least work-y note in a while - weeknotes #40</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-40/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-40/</guid><description>Still in France. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to find a rhythm with my folks who in fairness are doing their best to help us with looking after the little one. Despite our excellent relationship, it can be frustrating at times.
But for all the interruptions and short-notice changes of plans, two great things happened this week.
One, I got to spend one night and almost two full days in Paris. My work appointments fell through last minute but I guess I only had more time to spend with my friends, so no harm done.</description></item><item><title>Like layers of an onion - weeknotes #39</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-39/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-39/</guid><description>This note comes to you from France, where my little family has relocated for the next few weeks as a way to deal with the summer closure of the daycare centre.
There are worst places in the world to seek help from the family. Particularly since my dad has bought himself (or so he thinks) a gravel bike.
It took me a while since we worked with Niko on this for a whole afternoon, but I&amp;rsquo;ve now put up the pull request into the Digital Evidence Toolkit that brings functional elements and namespacing to the codebase.</description></item><item><title>Waldzweisamkeit - weeknotes #38</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-38/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-38/</guid><description>It was really hot. Nobody at home was feeling well. Didn&amp;rsquo;t do a huge amount of work, if I&amp;rsquo;m honest.
In a sudden burst of Waldzweisamkeit, I spent quite a few evenings in the forest, my local gravel cycling trails, so to speak. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice place for a quiet drink in the evening, though the hunt for cool temperatures last week was a lost cause.
We all got our first dose of the Covid vaccine, just in time for our travels to France the coming week.</description></item><item><title>Spanner in the works - weeknotes #37</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-37/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-37/</guid><description>Well, this is yet another note I end up publishing on Monday morning. I should probably aim for a different schedule: it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like I can make Friday evenings most weeks.
In my defense, it was a difficult week. The little one had an eye infection thing which meant no daycare. We took it as a bit of a challenge and while both of us did some work, my overall feeling is that I spent the week coping with the bits and bobs that needed doing right now while being constantly interrupted.</description></item><item><title>News in brief - weeknotes #36</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-36/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-36/</guid><description>Excellent week! It was the return of our nanny after two weeks off, and it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say we were all very, very happy to have her again.
Just as the week was tailing off, Charles asked if I could do a little extra for the Bureau Local about yet another very interesting story. More on this when it&amp;rsquo;s finally out.
For now, I get to audit their data and methodology, as well as to review some Python code.</description></item><item><title>Touch-and-go week - weeknotes #35</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-35/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-35/</guid><description>Bit of a special week which was all, as per the headline, touch-and-go. Monday was a public holiday in Germany, then my partner and I alternated looking after the little one during the afternoons as our nanny was off. Throw in an occasional errand and a walk-in doctor&amp;rsquo;s appointment and you&amp;rsquo;ve got a rather weird week!
We had nevertheless decided to keep to our &amp;ldquo;sprint&amp;rdquo; plan with the Deutsche Welle, which kept me busy most of the week.</description></item><item><title>Note with personal notes - weeknotes #34</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-34/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-34/</guid><description>If everything went well, you should be reading an HTML document served from a new place. Scaleway are discontinuing the small 4-ARM-CPU, dedicated instance this website called home for the last five to seven years.
I&amp;rsquo;m a little sad to see you go, C1 👋
In other personal news, we had the support of my parents this week, who came to stay with us this week. They helped us clock in full working days (minus the many coffee breaks) in exchange for lovely family dinners.</description></item><item><title>Good busy and Toolkit progress - weeknotes #33</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-33/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-33/</guid><description>It was a really fun week, I think. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it was busy – but maybe the right kind of busy ™️.
I even managed to squeeze in an afternoon in the park on baby duties, taking in the sun (which did not last) and chatting with Fellow Young Parents about our common experience.
I spent a bit more time designing the Digital Evidence Toolkit – as in, from the problem-definition and breaking up perspective:</description></item><item><title>Full steam ahead - weeknotes #32</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-32/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-32/</guid><description>For the first time since I was awarded the grant, I got to spend several consecutive days on the Digital Evidence Toolkit. I liked this pace: it felt like this wasn&amp;rsquo;t a hobby, but my job proper. I hope this continues through the spring and summer.
It currently feels like I am in a jungle, surrounded by tall grass and trees. I&amp;rsquo;ve got my imaginary machete and am just whacking trying to find a way through.</description></item><item><title>Deutsche Welle sprint - weeknotes #31</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-31/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-31/</guid><description>I worked all week on a sprint for Deutsche Welle, in company of three other people – including Niko.
The sprint format isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly my favourite thing in the world, and it&amp;rsquo;s all kinds of equally terrible on video conference.
Nevertheless we got quite a bit done on the KID project, which is a gamified verification challenge aiming to teach the ropes to media-curious people. Think reverse-image search, geolocation, and all round skepticism about digital media encountered online.</description></item><item><title>The new normal settles in - weeknotes #30</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-30/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-30/</guid><description>30th weeknote 🤘
Second week of the “new normal”, my partner having started working again. All clear, it&amp;rsquo;s been good fun so far, and we&amp;rsquo;re not suffering from the emergency daycare measures for the little one. Fingers crossed it stays like this!
Quite a bit of work on the Digital Evidence Toolkit:
I&amp;rsquo;ve done some sketching of what I&amp;rsquo;d like the API to look like (and made a fool of myself trying to implement some of it in Clojure) ; As I was translating some requirements from the Berkeley Protocol on Digital Open Source Investigations, I felt like I needed to explore how far out of my reach would a verifiable, signed ledger implementation be ; I read a really cool paper about verifying and authenticating a digital media by inserting a digital certificate inside the file (a JPEG in the paper) while preserving its structure.</description></item><item><title>Finally moving on - weeknotes #29</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-29/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-29/</guid><description>End of the longer-than-expected Tactical Tech rush. It&amp;rsquo;s in soft-launch and there are still types to harmonise, spacing to tighten and layouts to tweak – but overall we&amp;rsquo;re almost there.
I felt confident enough to announce that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be working full-time on this and that I would now do the polishing part-time and from structured feedback as I needed to attent to other matters (and start billing elsewhere).
🎉, I guess!</description></item><item><title>Friday already? - weeknotes #28</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-28/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-28/</guid><description>Wait, is it Friday already?
Tactical Tech work shaping up. Now talking about publication with the Product and Infrastructure people over there.
Funny feeling when you tell someone your web app fits in 3MB of static files. No database, no container, no companion microservices. You can almost hear them breathe a sigh of relief.
As I was telling Paul earlier today, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to being done with this project so I can talk about other things&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Working from Factory - weeknotes #27</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-27/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-27/</guid><description>The little one now needs a negative Covid quick test if she&amp;rsquo;s got cold/flu symptoms to attend daycare. For those not well-versed in baby deets, this includes a runny nose or a cough and that&amp;rsquo;s, well, very often for a one-year-old when it&amp;rsquo;s 5C outside.
Kitas are closing Monday after next, and we&amp;rsquo;ll go back to &amp;ldquo;emergency care&amp;rdquo; until further notice. Unclear what that means in terms of how many hours they&amp;rsquo;ll take her&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>A bout of fever - weeknotes #26</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-26/</guid><description>26th weeknotes, published on March 26. Well, maybe March 27, actually, who knows?
It&amp;rsquo;s been a crazy week, I thought today was the 23rd.
The little one had a bout of fever. That meant hospital, being shouted at profusely, and quite frankly ridiculous nights.
The funny thing with these occasions is how quickly your priorities redefine themselves. For example, I&amp;rsquo;m very much up against the clock for Tactical Tech but I can tell you I chose the extra sleep this morning – and I would do it again.</description></item><item><title>Busy busy - weeknotes #25</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-25/</guid><description>This is going to be a short one: I somehow didn&amp;rsquo;t take notes through the week.
Following rounds of feedback and very valuable suggestions (🙌), RadarTech&amp;rsquo;s deadline is extended by six to eight months, well into November. As we were discussing how the work would take place over the coming year, we thought I could work two days in June, two days in September, and then keep some availability in between, and we should be good, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to help to launch the final product since we designed it four months before.</description></item><item><title>Hello, Digital Evidence Toolkit - weeknotes #24</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-24/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-24/</guid><description>How is it Friday already? Where did this week go?
I finally (and somewhat belatedly) announced the funding and start of the Digital Evidence Preservation Toolkit, which I&amp;rsquo;m very excited about.
Please read the above post, and there&amp;rsquo;s also a newsletter I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep up-to-date.
Further trimming down on infrastructure at Global Witness Data and Investigations. I&amp;rsquo;m archiving and republishing two projects which currently run in a multi-parts docker-compose and on their own EC2 boxes.</description></item><item><title>Pick up the phone - weeknotes #23</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-23/</guid><description>The phone is your best friend. I always thought one&amp;rsquo;s willingness to ring people up made a difference in a newsroom. At least, every time I could be bothered to do it, it was very helpful.
This week, I was struggling with the Tactical Tech brief. As a solo freelancer, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel I can afford to be a little off from what the client has got in mind.
I rang Marek, and 15 minutes later not only things were clear but he also gave me a totally fresh perspective on what we could be doing.</description></item><item><title>Short week, short notes - weeknotes #22</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-22/</guid><description>Our nanny broke her toe at the weekend, so we were on our own on Monday, and didn&amp;rsquo;t know about Tuesday until late in the morning, leaving us to contemplate how fragile our ability to do a day&amp;rsquo;s work seems now.
Catchup with Bastien about dataviz for RadarTech, and design of the project in general. &amp;ldquo;Reach out when you need me to decide something that helps you pick a general direction over another,&amp;quot; he said.</description></item><item><title>Jaccard and dendrograms - weeknotes #21</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-21/</guid><description>The little one is spending more and more time at daycare, and I&amp;rsquo;m loving it.
It feels like it&amp;rsquo;s such a nice place for her, she&amp;rsquo;s got her own buddies and comes home hyper-stimulated. Meanwhile, I get to hang out with my internet buddies and be stimulated 😇
Despite having more time however, I had to kick the Tactical Tech deadline &amp;ndash; first time of my new freelance life I have to do that.</description></item><item><title>Bubbles bubbles - weeknotes #20</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-20/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s been perma-snow in Berlin for the last two weeks now. This weekend, hundreds of people were having a wander on the frozen canals. Two digits negative temperatures. Proper winter!
However, lockdown is going to last a while longer here in Germany. While the infection numbers are falling, the concern is the still-invisible surge of infections from the other variants, which would (according to some models) rocket up in the next three weeks and bring us the omniously-named Third Wave.</description></item></channel></rss>