<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Weeknotes on 👋 hi, I’m basile</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/</link><description>Recent content in Weeknotes on 👋 hi, I’m basile</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>No-time February - weeknotes #71, #72, #73, #74</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-71-72-73-74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-71-72-73-74/</guid><description>Hold on – March? I know February’s always a bit shorter than usual (I love this Britannica summary) but boy was this one short. I blame a combo of physical therapy (twice a week) and a whole lot of running (~120km this month, a lot by my standards) for the relative scarcity of long work days.
I started a couple of new things this month:
I joined a Correctiv/Beabee project creating a local-journalism-in-a-box software to enable communities to set up a membership system (💰) and interaction with their community.</description></item><item><title>50% of 50% January - weeknotes #67, #68, #69, #70</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-67-68-69-70/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-67-68-69-70/</guid><description>I’ve hardly opened emacs this month. Hadn’t hapenned in a while.
We came back from France early in the month and had somehow missed the memo about my daughter needing to quarantine for a week as she hasn’t gotten the vaccine yet (she doesn’t has strong feelings towards it, she’s just got a few years to wait).
Then, a mere day after the happy return to daycare it’s our nanny who tested positive, so we had to keep cruising on staggered work days for another week.</description></item><item><title>Festive December - weeknotes #63, #64, #65, #66</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-63-64-65-66/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-63-64-65-66/</guid><description>Welcome to my first monthnote written in the weeknote format.
I’ve had a ton of fun with note-taking this month and, for better or worse, have let go of graph-db-flavours of Roam (e.g. Athens). I went all in with Notion and despite the clunkiness of how Zettelkasten-type patterns work in it, I’ve not looked back yet.
Just wanted to highlight Jeff’s point one more time about the difference between a feature and a product:</description></item><item><title>Moving to a monthly format - weeknotes #62</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-62/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-62/</guid><description>Hello, December.
I probably won&amp;rsquo;t be publishing weekly notes this month, in a trial of a monthly format instead. I&amp;rsquo;ve moved some of my notes from org-roam to Notion and the upset in my life is simply too great for me to just write about at the minute.
Speak in a few weeks, then!</description></item><item><title>Write before the weekend - weeknotes #61</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-61/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-61/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m way behind writing these notes, but that may be because I&amp;rsquo;ve got little time on my hands these days. Seems like it&amp;rsquo;s busy as is every early winter, except this year it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of child care. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: it&amp;rsquo;s really cool and relaxing to chill out in bed or do puzzles. It just leaves less time to faff around the computer.
I&amp;rsquo;ve done a bit more work composing some of the UI elements and now charts I&amp;rsquo;m creating for the French survey project (the current status of which is a bit complicated to explain).</description></item><item><title>Short Parisian notes - weeknotes #60</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-60/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-60/</guid><description>Hi from Paris! Feels a bit odd to be travelling considering the seemingly sudden surge in Covid cases in Europe. Our apathy towards this in October and November being illustrated rather well by this Die Zeit viz:
This is what I love about #dataviz: its ability to point at *a problem*, to show it clearly, so we can then discuss it.
The example below is so powerful and graspable. Makes you wonder: how?</description></item><item><title>The Toolkit returns? - weeknotes #59</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-59/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-59/</guid><description>First week with an M1 laptop. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of insane, and it&amp;rsquo;s the little things. The instant wake and opening of apps. The whole-workday battery life. The total silence.
I followed up on a few leads for the Digital Evidence Toolkit, and it&amp;rsquo;s quite pleasant to see that some of them are still ongoing.
The plans remain the same, though: I&amp;rsquo;m still fleshing out options for either future work (collaboration on an org-wide instance, for example) or pivots (provide chain-of-custody as a service kind of a thing).</description></item><item><title>Long workshops - weeknotes #58</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-58/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-58/</guid><description>Hello, November!
I spent most of my working hours in workshops for the Deutsche Welle, who&amp;rsquo;s been given a pot of money to work on projects related to uses of AI to fight (mis/dis)information.
Lots of people in a Teams meeting&amp;hellip; turned out to not be so bad. Miro is an amazing tool and the workshop facilitators did a really good job of keeping the whole affair feeling snappy and quick!</description></item><item><title>Old PHP, and where does the Moon rise? - weeknotes #57</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-57/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-57/</guid><description>Dealing with ageing bespoke-built content: never fun. I hope that the tools we use today (static-files generation, lockfiles, containerisation, etc.) will make that job easier in the long run.
Even so, tools churn will remain a factor. This week, I looked at an old interactive web campaign, commissioned by Global Witness and built by capable people, in a mix of techs commonly referred to as a LAMP stack and updated a couple of years ago into a Docker orchestration.</description></item><item><title>Cryptic updates and Moon things - weeknotes #56</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-56/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-56/</guid><description>Chaperoning the little one to her new daycare centre is coming to an end, after the successful completion of more mini milestones such as napping, saying goodbye to me in the morning, and accepting to change nappies during the day.
Staying available for several hours a day in case the all-important nap wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work was rather annoying, however. Like, 3/10 quality of work.
The highlight of the week is the start of a series of coaching sessions aiming to inform broad reflexions about whatever it is I do as an occupation.</description></item><item><title>Very, very part-time - weeknotes #55</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-55/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-55/</guid><description>Second week of introductions to the new childcare centre. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s moving in the right direction – excellent news since in the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;m working very very part-time.
My folks were also visiting us this week. It was such a great timing because they really could help us and got to experience first-hand why Berlin&amp;rsquo;s been so great for us as young parents, including meeting the new daycare team and getting their take on the two education systems.</description></item><item><title>Speccing = cool - weeknotes #54</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-54/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-54/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working about 50% this week as I&amp;rsquo;m chaperoning the little one in her introduction to the new daycare centre. Which means that I spent my mornings with a group of about a dozen 2-6 year olds – a relatively different bunch than my regular colleagues, believe me.
I won&amp;rsquo;t bore you with parental softness, but it&amp;rsquo;s a really sweet thing seeing her navigating this new world and having so much to take on, from the new everyday language (🇫🇷) to the many rules of this new, strange place.</description></item><item><title>Blowing it - weeknotes #53</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-53/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-53/</guid><description>One of the most significant bits of last week is that I blew a technical interview. I had never done one before but thought I could navigate my way around doing some kind of d3.js thing under time pressure.
Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t. The task wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly difficult but my mistake was to think I had enough React under my belt. Nope. Everything from function signatures to patterns which are literally part of the standard library evaded me.</description></item><item><title>A year of weeknotes - weeknotes #52</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-52/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-52/</guid><description>One year writing these notes.
When I started, I was very much trying to go back to work, struggling to find more than a few hours here and there.
Since then:
I found work 🎉 and negotiated my rate and conditions with different kinds of clients, I got to say no to assignments for various reasons, When it got too busy or difficult, I set boundaries and made time for flexibility and family (the huge perks of this lifestyle), And since today, I lived through the difficulty of having to dump a client.</description></item><item><title>Stack jumping every day - weeknotes #51</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-51/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-51/</guid><description>Back to work after a week off, and now approaching a year of writing these weekly notes. I had lots of life admin stuff to do early in the week – things I had left for later after some time focusing solely on the Toolkit.
This week was the first week &amp;ldquo;after&amp;rdquo; the Toolkit, and I chopped it down into three clients.
I worked two full days for Deutsche Welle, the German broadcaster.</description></item><item><title>Speak soon - weeknotes #50</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-50/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-50/</guid><description>I have been on holiday and cycling around Angela Merkel&amp;rsquo;s adopted homeland: the Uckermark, a district north of Berlin and south of the Baltic Sea.
Nothing much to report, and certainly no work at all!</description></item><item><title>Hello from the holiday side - weeknotes #49</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-49/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-49/</guid><description>Well, there we are: September. Closing in on a year of such weeknotes now.
I’m writing this from an iPad and gitpod.io, a web browser-based dev environment. I didn’t think we had come this far with usability, to be honest. I’ve got a REPL running on the JVM running in another tab, all the nice VSCode extensions and my own little dev environment and preferences, and I didn’t save anything when I closed the laptop Berlin and packed the iPad.</description></item><item><title>Not so momentous after all - weeknotes #48</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-48/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-48/</guid><description>There is no overarching theme to this week&amp;rsquo;s notes. These two weeks (this past, about which you&amp;rsquo;re reading, and this coming, during which you&amp;rsquo;re reading this) are a bit of a lull:
The grant for the Toolkit is ending but has not quite ended yet ; we&amp;rsquo;re about to go away on holiday ; and I&amp;rsquo;m contemplating being back to my previous projects in a few weeks' time.
The end of the grant will be a sort of send off, a deluge of social media promotion of our projects.</description></item><item><title>The beginning of the end - weeknotes #47</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-47/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-47/</guid><description>This week felt like the beginning of the end of my grant dedicated to working on the Digital Evidence Toolkit. There were two internal deadlines having to do with public comms that will take place over the next two weeks, which meant that there was quite a lot to rush through so it would make MVP.
Time to relax, then? Well, I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure. This coming week is busy with pitch meetings and I&amp;rsquo;ve got the feeling it&amp;rsquo;s actually only the easy part that&amp;rsquo;s ending now: in two weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll be out there with what I&amp;rsquo;ve built, other jobs to do and no booked time to focus on the Toolkit anymore.</description></item><item><title>Expect not too much personal news - weeknotes #46</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-46/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-46/</guid><description>Second-to-last business week before submitting the v1.0 deliverables for the Digital Evidence Toolkit. Perhaps unsurprisingly, it&amp;rsquo;s all I did this week.
Last week, I wrote:
Turns out I’m being asked to show the product a lot. My answer so far is that it’s visually un-interesting and that the value proposition is in the technicalities more than in the design. Still, I feel I should oblige.
To help me with this, I commissioned La Loma, a Berlin-based design agency whose visual vocabulary I really love.</description></item><item><title>The pace picks up - weeknotes #45</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-45/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-45/</guid><description>Big week on the Digital Evidence Toolkit. We&amp;rsquo;re in the home stretch and I feel the pressure mounting.
I spent a bit of time doing further work on editing records, as well as designing some of the static assets for promotion, social media, etc. Turns out I&amp;rsquo;m being asked to show the product a lot.
My answer so far is that it&amp;rsquo;s visually un-interesting and that the value proposition is in the technicalities more than in the design.</description></item><item><title>Second shot, missed tile - weeknotes</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-44/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-44/</guid><description>I got to visit the Berlin Velodrom, though not to dawdle and look at pretty track bikes but to receive my second shot. In keeping with my life story so far, I received the Pfizer/BionTech (🇩🇪) after a first injection of Astra (🇬🇧).
Spent a work day at a new coworking in Neukölln, with an AC, a pantry full of fruits and drinks, and a symmetrical gigabit connection. As I wrote before: it&amp;rsquo;s the leaving to work and the being away at work that feels different.</description></item><item><title>Back to Germany - weeknotes #43</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-43/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-43/</guid><description>Wow, this feels like the beginning of the week was a really long time away. We&amp;rsquo;re now back in Berlin and getting in the groove again. We&amp;rsquo;ve got daycare, I&amp;rsquo;ve got my work setup and my bikes.
Earlier this week, on our last evening in France, we even had our second evening out while my parents looked after the little one.
I sinked more than a half-day on debugging an issue with Gatsby.</description></item><item><title>Short week shot note - weeknotes #42</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-42/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-42/</guid><description>Once again, hello from France, though from quite a bit more South than previously. It&amp;rsquo;s been pouring for the last three weeks in Lyon, so we drove down to la Drôme provençale: the bit in between Lyon and the Riviera/Marseille, a lovely and quiet piece of nature.
Coaching session on Thursday. We moved from &amp;ldquo;North Star&amp;rdquo; metrics we set last time to road-mapping.
The end of the grant period is nigh, and having an external point of view on the schedule and the MVP bucket list.</description></item><item><title>First-class history hoops - weeknotes #41</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-41/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-41/</guid><description>Still in France. I&amp;rsquo;ve not dont a tremendous amount of work this week due to a general lack of time and focus. Everybody&amp;rsquo;s doing their best but sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s just challenging.
Work opportunities keep coming – and I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for it. Most notable this week was a job for the Bureau of Investigative Journalism, which looks manageable in time and quite interesting.
Good progress on the Digital Evidence Toolkit.</description></item><item><title>The least work-y note in a while - weeknotes #40</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-40/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-40/</guid><description>Still in France. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to find a rhythm with my folks who in fairness are doing their best to help us with looking after the little one. Despite our excellent relationship, it can be frustrating at times.
But for all the interruptions and short-notice changes of plans, two great things happened this week.
One, I got to spend one night and almost two full days in Paris. My work appointments fell through last minute but I guess I only had more time to spend with my friends, so no harm done.</description></item><item><title>Like layers of an onion - weeknotes #39</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-39/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-39/</guid><description>This note comes to you from France, where my little family has relocated for the next few weeks as a way to deal with the summer closure of the daycare centre.
There are worst places in the world to seek help from the family. Particularly since my dad has bought himself (or so he thinks) a gravel bike.
It took me a while since we worked with Niko on this for a whole afternoon, but I&amp;rsquo;ve now put up the pull request into the Digital Evidence Toolkit that brings functional elements and namespacing to the codebase.</description></item><item><title>Waldzweisamkeit - weeknotes #38</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-38/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-38/</guid><description>It was really hot. Nobody at home was feeling well. Didn&amp;rsquo;t do a huge amount of work, if I&amp;rsquo;m honest.
In a sudden burst of Waldzweisamkeit, I spent quite a few evenings in the forest, my local gravel cycling trails, so to speak. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice place for a quiet drink in the evening, though the hunt for cool temperatures last week was a lost cause.
We all got our first dose of the Covid vaccine, just in time for our travels to France the coming week.</description></item><item><title>Spanner in the works - weeknotes #37</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-37/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-37/</guid><description>Well, this is yet another note I end up publishing on Monday morning. I should probably aim for a different schedule: it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like I can make Friday evenings most weeks.
In my defense, it was a difficult week. The little one had an eye infection thing which meant no daycare. We took it as a bit of a challenge and while both of us did some work, my overall feeling is that I spent the week coping with the bits and bobs that needed doing right now while being constantly interrupted.</description></item><item><title>News in brief - weeknotes #36</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-36/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-36/</guid><description>Excellent week! It was the return of our nanny after two weeks off, and it&amp;rsquo;s fair to say we were all very, very happy to have her again.
Just as the week was tailing off, Charles asked if I could do a little extra for the Bureau Local about yet another very interesting story. More on this when it&amp;rsquo;s finally out.
For now, I get to audit their data and methodology, as well as to review some Python code.</description></item><item><title>Touch-and-go week - weeknotes #35</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-35/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-35/</guid><description>Bit of a special week which was all, as per the headline, touch-and-go. Monday was a public holiday in Germany, then my partner and I alternated looking after the little one during the afternoons as our nanny was off. Throw in an occasional errand and a walk-in doctor&amp;rsquo;s appointment and you&amp;rsquo;ve got a rather weird week!
We had nevertheless decided to keep to our &amp;ldquo;sprint&amp;rdquo; plan with the Deutsche Welle, which kept me busy most of the week.</description></item><item><title>Note with personal notes - weeknotes #34</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-34/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-34/</guid><description>If everything went well, you should be reading an HTML document served from a new place. Scaleway are discontinuing the small 4-ARM-CPU, dedicated instance this website called home for the last five to seven years.
I&amp;rsquo;m a little sad to see you go, C1 👋
In other personal news, we had the support of my parents this week, who came to stay with us this week. They helped us clock in full working days (minus the many coffee breaks) in exchange for lovely family dinners.</description></item><item><title>Good busy and Toolkit progress - weeknotes #33</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-33/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-33/</guid><description>It was a really fun week, I think. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it was busy – but maybe the right kind of busy ™️.
I even managed to squeeze in an afternoon in the park on baby duties, taking in the sun (which did not last) and chatting with Fellow Young Parents about our common experience.
I spent a bit more time designing the Digital Evidence Toolkit – as in, from the problem-definition and breaking up perspective:</description></item><item><title>Full steam ahead - weeknotes #32</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-32/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-32/</guid><description>For the first time since I was awarded the grant, I got to spend several consecutive days on the Digital Evidence Toolkit. I liked this pace: it felt like this wasn&amp;rsquo;t a hobby, but my job proper. I hope this continues through the spring and summer.
It currently feels like I am in a jungle, surrounded by tall grass and trees. I&amp;rsquo;ve got my imaginary machete and am just whacking trying to find a way through.</description></item><item><title>Deutsche Welle sprint - weeknotes #31</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-31/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-31/</guid><description>I worked all week on a sprint for Deutsche Welle, in company of three other people – including Niko.
The sprint format isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly my favourite thing in the world, and it&amp;rsquo;s all kinds of equally terrible on video conference.
Nevertheless we got quite a bit done on the KID project, which is a gamified verification challenge aiming to teach the ropes to media-curious people. Think reverse-image search, geolocation, and all round skepticism about digital media encountered online.</description></item></channel></rss>