<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Weeknotes on 👋 hi, I’m basile</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/</link><description>Recent content in Weeknotes on 👋 hi, I’m basile</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>No-time February - weeknotes #71, #72, #73, #74</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-71-72-73-74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-71-72-73-74/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hold on – March? I know February’s always a bit shorter than usual (I love this &lt;a href="https://www.britannica.com/story/why-are-there-only-28-days-in-february">Britannica summary&lt;/a>) but boy was this one short. I blame a combo of physical therapy (twice a week) and a whole lot of running (~120km this month, a lot by my standards) for the relative scarcity of long work days.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I started a couple of new things this month:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I joined a &lt;strong>Correctiv/Beabee project&lt;/strong> creating a &lt;strong>local-journalism-in-a-box&lt;/strong> software to enable communities to set up a membership system (💰) and interaction with their community. That will be ~10 days a month for the foreseeable, and is probably the largest codebase I’ve worked on. Everybody involved is remote, and it’s been good fun so far.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I also started a &lt;strong>collaboration with the Digital Threats to Democracy team at Global Witness&lt;/strong>, designing experiments &lt;strong>testing hypotheses about TikTok and political leaning.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And some things are carrying on:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>50% of 50% January - weeknotes #67, #68, #69, #70</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-67-68-69-70/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-67-68-69-70/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve hardly opened emacs this month. Hadn’t hapenned in a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We came back from France early in the month and had somehow missed the memo about my daughter needing to quarantine for a week as she hasn’t gotten the vaccine yet (she doesn’t has strong feelings towards it, she’s just got a few years to wait).&lt;br>
Then, a mere day after the happy return to daycare it’s our nanny who tested positive, so we had to keep cruising on staggered work days for another week. We’re now in the clear and testing the little one three times a week. It’s mandatory. Fingers crossed this works and is worth it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Festive December - weeknotes #63, #64, #65, #66</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-63-64-65-66/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-63-64-65-66/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to my first &lt;em>monthnote&lt;/em> written in the &lt;em>weeknote&lt;/em> format.&lt;br>
I’ve had a ton of fun with note-taking this month and, for better or worse, have let go of graph-db-flavours of &lt;a href="https://roamresearch.com/">Roam&lt;/a> (e.g. &lt;a href="http://athensresearch.org/">Athens&lt;/a>). I went all in with Notion and despite the clunkiness of how Zettelkasten-type patterns work in it, I’ve not looked back yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just wanted to highlight Jeff’s point one more time about the difference between a &lt;em>feature&lt;/em> and a &lt;em>product&lt;/em>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving to a monthly format - weeknotes #62</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-62/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-62/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, December.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I probably won&amp;rsquo;t be publishing weekly notes this month, in a trial of a monthly format instead. I&amp;rsquo;ve moved some of my notes from &lt;a href="https://github.com/org-roam/org-roam/">org-roam&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://www.notion.so/">Notion&lt;/a> and the upset in my life is simply too great for me to just write about at the minute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speak in a few weeks, then!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Write before the weekend - weeknotes #61</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-61/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-61/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m way behind writing these notes, but that may be because I&amp;rsquo;ve got little time on my hands these days. Seems like it&amp;rsquo;s busy as is every early winter, except this year it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of child care. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: it&amp;rsquo;s really cool and relaxing to chill out in bed or do puzzles. It just leaves less time to faff around the computer.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="assets/radartech-camembert.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve done a bit more work composing some of the UI elements and now charts I&amp;rsquo;m creating for the French survey project (the current status of which is a bit complicated to explain). Above is a new chart type, inspired by the [State of Dataviz 2020/21], composing with highlights and pull-outs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Short Parisian notes - weeknotes #60</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-60/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-60/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi from Paris! Feels a bit odd to be travelling considering the seemingly sudden surge in Covid cases in Europe. Our apathy towards this in October and November being illustrated rather well by this Die Zeit viz:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet">&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr">This is what I love about &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/dataviz?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#dataviz&lt;/a>: its ability to point at *a problem*, to show it clearly, so we can then discuss it.&lt;br>&lt;br>The example below is so powerful and graspable. Makes you wonder: how? why? &lt;a href="https://t.co/xJzGINKlYb">https://t.co/xJzGINKlYb&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Toolkit returns? - weeknotes #59</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-59/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-59/</guid><description>&lt;p>First week with an M1 laptop. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of insane, and it&amp;rsquo;s the little things. The instant wake and opening of apps. The whole-workday battery life. The total silence.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I followed up on a few leads for the &lt;a href="https://digitalevidencetoolkit.org/">Digital Evidence Toolkit&lt;/a>, and it&amp;rsquo;s quite pleasant to see that some of them are still ongoing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The plans remain the same, though: I&amp;rsquo;m still fleshing out options for either future work (collaboration on an org-wide instance, for example) or pivots (provide chain-of-custody as a service kind of a thing).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Long workshops - weeknotes #58</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-58/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-58/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, November!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I spent most of my working hours in workshops for the Deutsche Welle, who&amp;rsquo;s been given a pot of money to work on projects related to uses of AI to fight (mis/dis)information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lots of people in a Teams meeting&amp;hellip; turned out to not be so bad. Miro is an amazing tool and the workshop facilitators did a really good job of keeping the whole affair feeling snappy and quick!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Old PHP, and where does the Moon rise? - weeknotes #57</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-57/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-57/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dealing with ageing bespoke-built content: never fun. I hope that the tools we use today (static-files generation, lockfiles, containerisation, etc.) will make that job easier in the long run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even so, tools churn will remain a factor. This week, I looked at an old interactive web campaign, commissioned by Global Witness and built by capable people, in a mix of techs commonly referred to as a LAMP stack and updated a couple of years ago into a Docker orchestration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cryptic updates and Moon things - weeknotes #56</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-56/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-56/</guid><description>&lt;p>Chaperoning the little one to her new daycare centre is coming to an end, after the successful completion of more mini milestones such as napping, saying goodbye to me in the morning, and accepting to change nappies during the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Staying available for several hours a day in case the all-important nap wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work was rather annoying, however. Like, 3/10 quality of work.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>The highlight of the week is the start of a series of coaching sessions aiming to inform broad reflexions about whatever it is I do as an occupation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Very, very part-time - weeknotes #55</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-55/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-55/</guid><description>&lt;p>Second week of introductions to the new childcare centre. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s moving in the right direction – excellent news since in the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;m working very very part-time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My folks were also visiting us this week. It was such a great timing because they really could help us &lt;em>and&lt;/em> got to experience first-hand why Berlin&amp;rsquo;s been so great for us as young parents, including meeting the new daycare team and getting their take on the two education systems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speccing = cool - weeknotes #54</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-54/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-54/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working about 50% this week as I&amp;rsquo;m chaperoning the little one in her introduction to the new daycare centre. Which means that I spent my mornings with a group of about a dozen 2-6 year olds – a relatively different bunch than my regular colleagues, believe me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won&amp;rsquo;t bore you with parental softness, but it&amp;rsquo;s a really sweet thing seeing her navigating this new world and having so much to take on, from the new everyday language (🇫🇷) to the many rules of this new, strange place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blowing it - weeknotes #53</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-53/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-53/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most significant bits of last week is that I blew a technical interview. I had never done one before but thought I could navigate my way around doing some kind
of d3.js thing under time pressure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t. The task wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly difficult but my mistake was to think I had enough React under my belt. Nope. Everything from function signatures to patterns
which are literally part of the standard library evaded me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A year of weeknotes - weeknotes #52</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-52/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-52/</guid><description>&lt;p>One year writing these notes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started, I was very much trying to go back to work, struggling to find more than a few hours here and there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since then:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I found work 🎉 and negotiated my rate and conditions with different kinds of clients,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I got to say no to assignments for various reasons,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When it got too busy or difficult, I set boundaries and made time for flexibility and family (the huge perks of this lifestyle),&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And since today, I lived through the difficulty of having to dump a client.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>A year into this notes is as good a time as any to think about these full-time employment opportuinities that arise every so often. It would mean no more admin, no more thinking I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;losing&amp;rdquo; a day&amp;rsquo;s wages when I&amp;rsquo;m doing things for myself. Ah well, I&amp;rsquo;ll choose on merit of each opportuinity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stack jumping every day - weeknotes #51</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-51/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/weeknotes/weeknotes-51/</guid><description>&lt;p>Back to work after a week off, and now approaching a year of writing these weekly notes. I had lots of &lt;em>life admin&lt;/em> stuff to do early in the week – things I had left for later after some time focusing solely on the Toolkit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week was the first week &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;after&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> the Toolkit, and I chopped it down into three clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>I worked two full days for Deutsche Welle, the German broadcaster. No meetings, just logging in and doing some work. I spent this time reviewing the codebase for a project called KID, which has to do with training resources about disinformation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>