<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio on 👋 hi, I’m basile</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/tags/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio on 👋 hi, I’m basile</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basilesimon.fr/tags/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Portfolio case study: Machine learning's take on Brexit</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-brexit-rift-machine-learning/?ref=rss</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-brexit-rift-machine-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>An original data-driven experiment looking at how Brexit splits the Tories. Modelling of a dataset to test a hypothesis.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="project-course">Project course&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The project came to be as a backburner piece for my contribution to the Europe, Middle East and Africa Reuters file: a kind of backgrounder, explainer story we could mention and push out again every once in a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The central question was whether we could back up the feeling Lobby reporters had that there were several groups of Tories, so-called &amp;ldquo;tribes,&amp;rdquo; with different attitudes to Brexit — while Labour parliamentarians were relatively united in pushing back against Theresa May&amp;rsquo;s deal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Portfolio case study: Reuters' 2019 general election results page</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-general-election-2019-britain/?ref=rss</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-general-election-2019-britain/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="assets/ge2019-header.png" alt="Intro to GE2019 page screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A node backend and a modular, reactive front page visualising the UK general election results, as they happened. For Reuters Graphics.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, this page was deleted from the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="front-end-the-results-page">Front end: the results page&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The page was built to be modular, i.e. to work this way:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>clients must be able to pick and choose which graphics they want, from one of them to all of them,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>there is only one repository of code I update and push out to clients.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>So the main app itself is broken down into sections which are totally independent from one another.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Portfolio case study: Global Witness' Pipedown interactive map</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-global-witness-pipedown-map/?ref=rss</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/portfolio-global-witness-pipedown-map/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="assets/gw-full.png" alt="Pipedown screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>An interactive map of natural gas infrastructure in the EU, built with Svelte and d3, for Global Witness.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="some-context">Some context&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The EU has a rule in place to regulate which electricity and fossil fuel projects it will financially support. These projects include the terminals and pipelines used to import and transport fossil gas – sometimes referred to as natural gas. Under this regulation, selected gas projects get fast-track approval and access to billions in public subsidies.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>