<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>d3 on 👋 hi, I’m basile</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/tags/d3/</link><description>Recent content in d3 on 👋 hi, I’m basile</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://basilesimon.fr/tags/d3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Some declarative, React-like logic for your Observable/d3 toolkit</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/hello-d3-render/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/hello-d3-render/</guid><description>Earlier this week, as I was looking into idiomatic ways of updating a chart, I came across Kaho Cheung&amp;rsquo;s d3-render &amp;ndash; and boy did I get excited.
d3-render packages up a bunch of d3 commands in a declarative shell, inspired by a eather functional and reactive approach. @unkleho has got a lovely tutorial introducing the library, but here&amp;rsquo;s another one from yours truly anyway.
Implementation It&amp;rsquo;s going to work this way:</description></item><item><title>A beeswarm layout in Observable -- on deadline</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/observable-beeswarm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/observable-beeswarm/</guid><description>I recently had to complete a technical test for a role I&amp;rsquo;m interested in.
The task: from a story out of the Global Witness website, can you come up with an alternative visualisation? You&amp;rsquo;ve got two hours.
As there were no embed constraints, I figured there was no point in faffing with boilerplate code and scaffolds, so I went down the Observable route to put a chart together.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what we need scales-wise:</description></item><item><title>Machine learning's take on the Brexit's House of Commons</title><link>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/brexit-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://basilesimon.fr/blog/brexit-machine-learning/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say things are a little confused over here in Brexit Land. To put it lightly, it has become difficult to explain, or simply to fathom what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next.
A few months ago I looked at the rift splitting the Conservative Party, but the topic kept nagging me.
Obviously the &amp;ldquo;indicative votes&amp;rdquo; were a great tool to identify the Brexit &amp;ldquo;tribes,&amp;quot; as they represented such varied opinions, allowing us to build a mental picture of the different kinds of Brexit MPs could support.</description></item></channel></rss>